Guide to the Sol Yurick Manuscripts for Publication TAM.268
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sol Yurick Manuscripts for Publication
1940-2012
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Yurick, Sol, 1925-2013
Yurick, Adrienne
TAM.268
43 Linear Feet in 38 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 oversize folder
1 VHS
6 audiocassettes
41.8 Megabytes on 612 computer files
The Sol Yurick Manuscripts for Publication (dated 1940-2012) consists of typed manuscripts and drafts written by novelist Sol Yurick (1925-2013). Yurick was a Brooklyn based writer who was best known for novels portraying poverty and violence in New York City in the 1960s and 1970s. The collection contains drafts and manuscripts of Yurick's published works, as well as manuscripts that were intended for, but never reached publication. Other materials in the collection include correspondence, contracts, and royalty statements related to the publication of his novels and stories. It also contains a small amount of personal items such as diaries, personal correspondence, and materials related to Yurick's teaching.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Sol Yurick in 1985; additional materials were donated by Adrienne Yurick in 2014. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1950.090 and 2014.008.
Arrangement
The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained. Materials in this collection have not been arranged by an archivist.
Biographical Note
Sol Yurick (1925-2013) was an American author based in New York City, who was best known for novels portraying poverty and urban life in the 1960s and 1970s. Born in Manhattan on January 18, 1925, Yurick grew up in the Bronx where he attended the Bronx High School of Science. After high school he enlisted in the United States Army where he trained as a surgical technician during World War II. Following his military service he enrolled in New York University and graduated with a BA in English in 1951. He later received an MA in English from Brooklyn College. Yurick worked for several years as an investigator for the New York City Department of Welfare. His first book, The Warriors, drew from his experience with the Department of Welfare and portrayed gang violence as a product of poverty rather than social dysfunction. Loosely based on the classical Greek story Anabasis, Yurick sought to provide a more accurate portrayal of gang violence that contrasted the glamorized images in pop culture such as West Side Story. The Warriors was later turned into a motion picture in 1979, which garnered a strong cult following.
Yurick's next two novels Fertig (1966) and The Bag (1968) likewise reflected Yurick's views on urban poverty and municipal bureaucracy. Fertig, which tells the story of a father who seeks revenge on hospital administrators and doctors whose neglect contributed to the death of his son, serves as a critique of health care bureaucracy. His novel The Bag focused on race and class relations in 1960s on the streets of New York City. Fertig, was also adapted into a film, which was retitled Confession (1999), and featured Alec Baldwin and Ben Kingsley. Yurick's other works include a collection of short stories titled Someone Just Like You (1972); an anthology titled Voices of Brooklyn (1973); and several novels including, An Island Death (1976), Richard A (1981), and Behold Metatron: The Recording Angel (1985). He also wrote several essays and short stories for the academic journal Social Text, and in the 1960s contributed to the Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) tract "Who Runs Columbia".
Yurck lived in Park Slope, Brooklyn with his wife Adrienne. He died in January of 2013.
Scope and Contents
This collection principally consists of typed manuscripts of novelist Sol Yurick's published and unpublished works. Yurick's writings include numerous drafts of his novels, essays, short stories, and plays. These manuscripts cover much of Yurick's career from his early writings in the mid-1940s to the early 2000s. The collection contains several versions of his drafts, which show the various stages of Yurick's writing process, and contain the author's edits and revisions. Many of the manuscripts in this collection eventually resulted in published versions, but the collection also contains manuscripts of unpublished works.
The collection also contains a small number of materials related to Yurick's publications including correspondence with publishers, materials related to royalties, contracts, reviews, and documents related to film adaptations of Yurick's work. These materials include a small amount of personal items including correspondence with family and friends, journals, and papers related to Yurick's political activism.
Titles of Yurick's drafts have been maintained as best as possible. Many of these titles appear in abbreviated or alternate forms, which Yurick used throughout his editing process. Additionally, there are many cases in which the pages within Yurick's drafts appear out of order. Throughout the editing process, Yurick often included additional pages to his drafts or renumbered certain sections. Consequently, there are a number of instances where pages will appear to be repetitive, missing, or out of order. While this is partially reflective of Yurick's editing methodology, there are also a number of instances where loose drafts and fragments became out of order prior to being archived, the original order of which is difficult to discern.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Manuscripts for publication.; Essays.; Short stories.; Novelists, American -- 20th century.; Political fiction, American.; Literature, Modern -- 20th century.; Marxist criticism.; Technology and civilization; Yurick, Sol, 1925-2013; Yurick, Adrienne
- "The Large Door", 1948-1965 (Box 1)
- Untitled Fragment, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
- "The Last S-F Story", 1948-1950 (Box 1)
- "Immolation: A Short Story", 1947-1950 (Box 1)
- "Companion of Virgil and Homer", 1947-1949 (Box 1)
- "The Lot of God", circa 1948-1949 (Box 1)
- "Schedule", circa 1940-1959 (Box 1)
- Various drafts-"The Flagellants," "Founders' Day", undated (Box 1)
- Untitled Fragment, 1947-1949 (Box 1)
- "Story of a Man Who Thought He Was Blind", 1947-1949 (Box 1)
- "Beauty and the Beast", 1947-1948 (Box 1)
- Untitled, undated (Box 1)
- "The Siege", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 1)
- "The Anneling" (early version of the Noble Savage), undated (Box 1)
- "The Flight", circa 1958 (Box 1)
- Early Short Stories, undated (Box 1)
- "The Second Coming", undated (Box 1)
- Richard A, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 1)
- "To Win Me Soon", 1944-1955, undated; 6 folders 6 folders (Box 1)
- Notes and Proposals, undated, 1994-1996, 2000, 2006, 2008-2012
  - Paper, undated; 14 folders (Box 2)
  - Electronic Records, 1994-1996, 2000, 2006, 2008-2012; TW_TAM_268_ER_24
- Prototypes of Biography and Curriculum Vitae, undated, 1997-1999, 2008-2009
  - Paper, undated (Box 2)
  - Electronic Records, 1997-1999, 2008-2009; TW_TAM_268_ER_30
- "The Political Economy of Sexual Liberation", undated (Box 2)
- "Politics" (notes), undated (Box 2)
- Fertig, undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 2)
- The Bag (notes and edits), undated, 2012; 5 folders 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Paper, undated; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Electronic Records, 2012; TW_TAM_268_ER_37
- "Counterintelligence for a Democratic Society" (notes and edits), undated (Box 3)
- "Disasters of a Summer's Hour The Pornography", undated (Box 3)
- "Fertig the Fulfillment", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 3)
- "R.E. Project", undated (Box 3)
- "Critic of Capitalism Goes Hollywood" by Robert M. Berkman (article discussing film adaptations of Yurick's work), 2002 (Box 3)
- "The Awakening", undated (Box 3)
- "The Awakening" (early version), undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 3)
- "...And Not in Utter Nakedness...", 1964 May 15 (Box 3)
- "The Child-God Dance", 1962 February 15 (Box 3)
- "Someone Just Like Me", 1963 March 28; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 3)
- "Do They Talk About Genet in Larchmont", undated (Box 3)
- "Welcome to the Tribe", undated (Box 3)
- "The Age of Gold", undated (Box 3)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 3)
- Note Cards and Typed Journal, 1963-1966, undated; 3 items 2 small boxes of Sol Yurick notes 1 bound volume containing Sol Yurick's typed journal (Box 4)
- Manuscripts - Correspondence, undated (Box 5)
- Assorted Manuscripts (fiction), undated; 6 folders 6 folders (Box 5)
- The Bag, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- Untitled Manuscript, undated (Box 5)
- "Anabasis V", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- "The Warriors", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- Untitled Manuscript, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- An Island Death, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- "The Warriors", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 6)
- Assorted Drafts and Political Writings, undated; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 6)
- "A Hunger for Dragons" Outline, undated (Box 6)
- Assorted Manuscripts (fiction), undated; 9 folders 9 folders (Box 6)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated, 1989-1992, 1995-1996, 2000, 2002, 2006, 2008
  - Paper, undated; 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Electronic Records, 1989-1992, 1995-1996, 2000, 2002, 2006, 2008; TW_TAM_268_ER_21
- Early session of the murders; Fertig; Later-"To Win Me Soon"; Early session of "The Biographical Novel", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 7)
- "The Awakening", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 7)
- "The Leaves and Fishes Program: Or; The Coming of the Cray III Christ", undated (Box 7)
- Correspondence and Biographical Information about Yurick, undated (Box 7)
- "The Bridegroom Cometh" (fragment), undated (Box 7)
- Fertig (fragment), undated (Box 7)
- "The Age of Gold", 1965 January 9 (Box 7)
- "The Sound of One Hand Clapping", 1964 January 21 (Box 7)
- "Tarantella", 1962 December 1 (Box 7)
- "The Social Psychology of Lynching: A Story", 1962 May 2 (Box 7)
- "Founders Day", undated (Box 7)
- "...And Know Not Me", undated (Box 7)
- "Baron's Lost", undated (Box 7)
- Assorted Fragments, undated (Box 7)
- "Precis for a Detective Novel", undated (Box 7)
- Untitled Fragment, undated (Box 7)
- "Living off the Land", undated (Box 7)
- "Class in America", undated (Box 7)
- "Empire", undated (Box 7)
- "The Sticking Point", undated (Box 7)
- "The Second Coming", undated (Box 7)
- "Dear Child, I Feared That You Were Dead" (Box 7)
- "Behold the Metatron: The Recording Angel", undated, 1994, 1996-1997, 2009
  - Paper, undated; 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Electronic Records, 1994, 1996-1997, 2009; TW_TAM_268_ER_4
- "The Harvesting", undated; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 8)
- An Island Death, undated (Box 8)
- The Bag, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Death", undated (Box 8)
- "The Destiny Algorithm/Sound Money Kill", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Faust as Stalin", undated (Box 8)
- "The Mutation of the Sociobeast", undated (Box 8)
- "The Hundred Gigaflop Snatch: A Treatment for a Screenplay", undated (Box 8)
- "The Fabulous Englishman" by Robert McCrum, Review by Yurick, undated (Box 8)
- "The Magic Kingdom" Stanley Elkins, "Dutton" Jerome Charyn, "War Cries Over Avenue C" Donald I. Fine, undated (Box 8)
- "The Art of Memory, Ancient and New", undated (Box 8)
- "Other People's Money: The Rise and Fall of OPM Leasing Services," Review by Yurick, undated (Box 8)
- "White Noise" by Don Delillo, Review by Yurick, undated (Box 8)
- "The One-Hundred Gigaflop Snatch: A Scenario", undated (Box 8)
- "The Hundred Gigaflop Snatch: A Scenario", undated (Box 8)
- "The Destiny Algorithm", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Classets", undated (Box 8)
- "The Twenty Megaflop Dump-snatch", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Rosemyth", undated (Box 8)
- "The Loaves and Fishes Program", undated (Box 8)
- "The Harvesting", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 8)
- "Sound Money Kill", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 9)
- "To Win Me Soon-Final Version", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 9)
- "The Bubble-Masters", undated (Box 9)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 9)
- "Burning", undated; 6 folders 6 folders (Box 9)
- "Burning-Part III", undated (Box 9)
- "Mission Control: Jesus? A Communist?", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 9, Box 10)
- "Purposes of Politics in the Imagination and an Outline", undated (Box 10)
- "Moby Dick as Politics and the New Novel", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 10)
- "Politics in the Imagination: Burning the Bank of America", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 10)
- "Burning the Bank of America", undated, 1991-1994, 2000, 2002, 2006-2008, 2010
  - Paper, undated (Box 10)
  - Electronic Records, 1991-1994, 2000, 2002, 2006-2008, 2010; TW_TAM_268_ER_6
- "The True Story of Oedipus", undated (Box 10)
- "In the Realm of the Angels", undated (Box 10)
- "Some Comments on Parts 2 and 3", undated (Box 10)
- Journals, 1948, 1960 (Box 11)
- Fertig (bound draft), undated (Box 12)
- Fertig (bound draft), undated (Box 13)
- "Politics in the Imagination: The Problem of Consciousness and the Symbols of Domination", undated (Box 14)
- Handwritten Notes, Drafts, and Diagrams, undated; 3 folders (Box 14)
- Proposal for a Course, undated (Box 14)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
- Assorted Essays and Short Stories, 1968-1969; 3 folders (Box 14, Box 15)
- An Island Death, undated; 4 folders (Box 15)
- An Island Death (galley proof), 1975 May 19 (Box 15)
- Someone Just Like You (proof), 1969 February 19; 2 folders (Box 15)
- "Jackie Marries Aristotle and Socrates Onassis: An Epithalamium" by The Gadfly, undated (Box 15)
- "The Political Economy of Drugs", undated (Box 15)
- "On Making Policy with Your Feet", undated (Box 15)
- "Towards a Revolutionary Literary Consciousness and the Hand of the CIA and FBI as Commissioner of Aesthetic Works", undated; 2 folders (Box 15)
- Richard A (master copy II), undated; 5 folders (Box 15, Box 16)
- Behold the Metatron, The Recording Angel, undated; 2 folders (Box 16)
- "Project: The Harvesting", undated (Box 16)
- Manuscript for "Teshum-The Witness" by John Squire, 1984 May 30; 2 folders (Box 16)
- "Politics in the Imagination: Burning of the Bank of America", undated; 3 folders (Box 16)
- Letters and Correspondence: "Sound Money Kill", 1968-1980; 2 folders (Box 16)
- Correspondence, 1955-1984; 14 folders (Box 17, Box 16)
- "The King of Malaputa", circa 1991; 5 folders 5 folders (Box 17)
- Periodicals Containing Sol Yurick Articles: Bennington Review and Cinecast, 1969-1980 (Box 17)
- Correspondence with Tetsuo Kogawa, 1985-1995 (Box 17)
  - Paper, 1985-1995 (Box 17)
  - Electronic Records, 1980, 1990, 1993-1995, 2001; TW_TAM_268_ER_9
- Correspondence with Jan Pieterse, undated, 1980, 1985-1992, 2001
  - Paper, undated, 1985-1991 (Box 17)
  - Electronic Records, 1980, 1992, 2001; TW_TAM_268_ER_8
- Correspondence, 1977-2003; 1980-1990
  - Paper, 1977-2003; 1980-1990; 3 folders (Box 17, Box 18)
  - Electronic Records, 1980, 1988, 1991, 1993-2003, 2006-2012; TW_TAM_268_ER_10
- Flyers and Pamphlets on Art and Theater, 1978-1980, undated (Box 18)
- Flyers and Newsletters on Freedom of Speech and Expression, 1968, 1981, undated (Box 18)
- Royalty Statements, 1975-1996, 2006 (Box 18)
- Correspondence: Doubleday, 1982, 1986-1990 (Box 18)
- Speaking Engagements and Honorariums, 1985-1987, 1997 (Box 18)
- Postcards, 1963, 1983-1987 (Box 18)
- Correspondence: Georges Borchardt, 1985-2012 (Box 18)
- Correspondence: Yoshanan Lorwin, 1990-1993, 1999; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 18)
- Correspondence: Robert Coover, 1980-1981, 1994-1998
  - Paper, 1981-1998 (Box 18)
  - Electronic Records, 1980, 1994-1997; TW_TAM_268_ER_12
- Correspondence: Richard Carrier, 1998, 2002-2003 (Box 18)
- Teaching Materials, 1983, undated (Box 18)
- "Arthur," and Correspondence Regarding Publications, 1975-1985 (Box 18)
- Correspondence: John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 18)
- "Faust-Stages of Spiritual Economic Growth", undated (Box 18)
- "How the Athenians Planned...", undated (Box 18)
- Handwritten Notes and Questions "Malaputa", undated (Box 18)
- "OED Essay", 1994; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 18)
- "Virgin Birth Meditations", May - October 2004
  - Paper, May - October 2004
  - Electronic Records, 2004; TW_TAM_268_ER_45
- "Paradise", 2001 July - September (Box 18)
- "Age of Freemarket Metastate", undated, 1993, 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - Paper, undated (Box 19)
  - Electronic Records, 1993, 1995-1996; TW_TAM_268_ER_2
- "Political/Cultural Economy...", undated (Box 19)
- "Warriors as Allegory", undated (Box 19)
- "Warriors Essay", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 19)
- "Marx/James", undated, 1995, 2000-2008, 2012
  - Paper, 2000-2006; 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Electronic Records, 1995, 2000-2004, 2007-2008, 2012; TW_TAM_268_ER_22
- "Woodout", 1989-1994, undated; 6 folders 6 folders (Box 19)
- "Poli-OED", 1990-1994; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 19)
- "Faust" (Box 19)
- Articles and Newspaper Clippings- Reviews, 1965-1970; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 19)
- Articles and Ephemera- Political Activism, 1965-1986 (Box 19)
- Photographs from the 1979 Film adaptation of The Warriors (Box 19)
- "Moses Hall", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 19)
- "ESI", 1995 October - December; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 19, Box 20)
- "Deconstruction of Jews", 1990-1992, 1995, 2000-2001, 2008, 2011-2012
  - Paper, 1990-1992; 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Electronic Records, 1991-1992, 1995, 2000-2001, 2008, 2011-2012; TW_TAM_268_ER_13
- "OEDI Play", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 20)
- "Suicide", 1992 August - September; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 20)
- "Short takes", 1989-2003, 2006, 2008; 6 folders 6 folders (Box 20)
  - Paper, 1989-2003 (Box 20)
  - Electronic Records, 1996, 1999-2002, 2006, 2008; TW_TAM_268_ER_33
- "Poli-Oed (Athenians)", 1996; 2 folders (Box 20)
- "Jews", 1995 February - March (Box 20)
- "Burning of the Bank of America, or Politics in the Imagination of The Deconstruction of the Jews or The Blasted Cold-War Hearth", 1994 February (Box 20)
- "Suicide", 1991-1995 (Box 20)
- "How the Athenians Plotted to Infiltrate and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves", 1996 September - December (Box 20)
- "The Political Economy of the Imagination", undated, 1994-1995, 2000-2002
  - Paper, undated; 2 folders (Box 20, Box 21)
  - Electronic Records, 1994-1995, 2000-2002; TW_TAM_268_ER_41
- "Susanna Yurick"/"Consciousness", 2005 May 16 (Box 21)
- "Consciousness", undated (Box 21)
- "Loud," a novel by Russell T. Harrison, 1992 (Box 21)
- "The Religious Politics of the Delphic Priesthood" by Kevin Coogan, 1982 June 20 (Box 21)
- Article Recording Holocaust Museum, undated (Box 21)
- Sol's Highlighted Passages from Bible, undated (Box 21)
- "About Sid's Work" (essay in German by Wilfried Hulsemann), undated (Box 21)
- Works Sent to Saul, undated (Box 21)
- "Behold Metatron", undated (Box 21)
- "Metatron Speaks Again", 1996 January - March; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 21)
- "Metatron Index", undated (Box 21)
- "Metatron Speaks Again", undated (Box 21)
- "Bank Burning", 1990-2003; 7 folders 7 folders (Box 21)
- "Burning", 1990-1994; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 21)
- "Burnout", 1991 May - June (Box 22)
- "Destiny of Algorithm", 1992-1994; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 22)
- "European", 1994 May (Box 22)
- "Destiny of Algorithm Paradise", undated (Box 22)
- "Destiny of Algorithm Reshuffled", 2000 June (Box 22)
- "Destiny of (Pre) Algorithms", 2002; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 22)
- "Destiny of Algorithm Preconditions", undated (Box 22)
- "Euroiden", 1991-1995, 1999-2001
  - Paper, 1991-1993; 6 folders (Box 22)
  - Electronic Records, 1991, 1993-1995, 1999-2001; TW_TAM_268_ER_14
- "Eucharist", 2004 May (Box 22)
- "Reply to George", undated (Box 22)
- "Joseph", 1989 December (Box 22)
- "Bereshit/Great Escape", undated, 1994, 2000
  - Paper, undated (Box 22)
  - Electronic Records, 1994, 2000; TW_TAM_268_ER_5
- Personal items including Birth Certificate and Military Records, undated (Box 22)
- Ms. Magazine, 1977 May (Box 22)
- "The Political Economy of Literature", undated, 1999-2000, 2007
  - Paper, undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Electronic Records, 1999-2000, 2007; TW_TAM_268_ER_42
- Notes and Articles Related to Telecommunications, undated (Box 22)
- "Reply to Letter by George", undated (Box 22)
- "Memories in the Context of the End of the Cold War", undated (Box 22)
- "In the Paradise Theater", 1994, 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - Paper, July - August 2001 (Box 22)
  - Electronic Records, 1994, 2000-2001; TW_TAM_268_ER_18
- "Marx and James Meet in the Ahistorical Garden of Innocence", 2000 August 30 (Box 22)
- "Short Takes", 2001-2002 (Box 22)
- "The Destiny of Algorithm, Or: The King of Malaputa, Or: A Hunger for Dragons", 2000 June 14 (Box 22)
- Personal Items (includes address books, one art book, and an unlabeled photograph), undated, 2002
  - Paper, undated (Box 22)
  - Electronic Records, 2002; TW_TAM_268_ER_27
- "Marxist Detective Novel", undated, 2000
  - Paper, undated; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Electronic Records, 2000; TW_TAM_268_ER_35
- Papers Miscellaneous Current, undated (Box 23)
- Miscellaneous Letters Current, undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 23)
- "Malaputa", undated; 16 folders (Box 24, Box 25, Box 26)
- Lecture-discussion, undated (Box 26)
- "Faust/Yurick" - Manuscript "Faust's Stages of Spiritual/Economic Growth and Take off into Transcendence", undated (Box 26)
- "Faust/Yurick", undated; 2 folders 2 folders (Box 26)
- "Understanding the Context of the Iranagua or Iran-contra Conspiracy", undated (Box 26)
- "Faust's Stages of Spiritual/Economic Growth and Take off into Transcendence", undated, 1994-1995
  - Paper, undated; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Electronic Records, 1994-1995; TW_TAM_268_ER_48
- "Faust", undated; 3 folders 3 folders (Box 26)
- "Malaputa", undated (Box 27)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 17 folders 17 folders (Box 27)
- "Green Outline/Delbert", undated (Box 27)
- "Delbert and the Witch World of St. Cunegonde", undated (Box 27)
- "Directory Listing of C:\Malout", undated (Box 27)
- "Wooden O/Within this Wooden O", undated (Box 27)
- "Malaputa", undated; 4 folders 4 folders (Box 28)
- "Suite Vengeance (with Dobson and Quigley)", undated (Box 28)
- "Dionysus at the Beach (with Dobson and Quigley)", undated (Box 28)
- "The Concert at the Beach (with Dobson and Quigley)", undated (Box 28)
- "Oedipus", 1988-1989; 6 folders 6 folders (Box 28)
- "The Future of the Information Age", undated (Box 28)
- "Within this Wooden O", undated (Box 28)
- Review of "The Postmodern Aura" by Charles Newman, undated (Box 28)
- "The Library", undated, 1980
  - Paper, undated (Box 28)